<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>dra4ov</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/"/>
 <updated>2024-05-14T09:20:42+03:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>estonia: year 2</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2024/05/13/year-2"/>
   <updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2024/05/13/year-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;year-2&quot;&gt;Year 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has now been 2 years since I packed my stuff into my Volkswagen and embarked on a little adventure called “moving to Estonia”. Honestly, time has flown by quick. I will go chronologically over all the events that remain in my memory from this time stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly 3 weeks after I arrived, I had just found an appartment to live in when Ukraine got invaded by Russia. I remember standing on the balcony—I might have been a little under the influence—looking out over a quiet neighbourhood dotted with apartment buildings. From tens of windows, a soft yellow light glowed, bearing witness to the many lives that were going on. It felt as if the peaceful sky above all this was somehow a deception and that it might burst at any moment, releasing a wave of insanity that would descend on these lives. It was not a very pleasant thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first year was spent working at a Finnish consultancy company. To be completely honest, I took the job as a stepping stone to be able to move to Estonia, so I shouldn’t complain, but the experience was not that great; it just confirmed/reinforced what I already knew: big companies are insanely unproductive, and I honestly don’t understand how they manage to get anything done at all. In this case, the company I worked for was Qualcomm, a big fish from the US of A. I thought, perhaps American companies are different from European ones? (My previous negative work experience was with Nokia). Turns out, no, they’re all the same. Actually, I think Qualcomm was considerably worse (at least the team I worked with), since it was completely overrun by Indians who, honestly, I wouldn’t trust with programming a traffic light (let alone telecom infrastructure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I didn’t move to Estonia without a “plan”. What might that be, you might ask. Here it goes: naturally, I’m not the most socially outgoing person, but after moving, I put it in my head that I had to try to keep my “social entropy” as high as possible (especially during that crucial first year). And honest to God— it kind of worked? I joined a co-working space, which was where I spent most of my Saturdays and Sundays (and eventually also working days, since I was so bored with the company office vibe). There, I did meet some cool people, but unfortunately, most of them were working on web development-related stuff (or crypto), and that’s just not what I was looking for (as I’m more into embedded/electronics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, before I moved, I had done some research; I knew I wanted to meet interesting people as fast as possible. The coworking space I eventually signed up for wasn’t the only place I had found that was (potentially) promising. I had also found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k-space.ee/&quot;&gt;K-Space&lt;/a&gt;, a hacker space. In the first month or so, I paid a visit to both. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lift99.co/&quot;&gt;Lift99&lt;/a&gt; (the coworking space) was pretty lively, had a table tennis table (heh), and was in a pretty cool, hipster-ish area. Visiting K-Space went as follows: there was one guy (very friendly!) who gave me a tour. They had some pretty cool old computers and a working area for soldering, woodwork, and so on, but it looked pretty empty as far as human activity goes. So, I made my choice by signing up for Lift99. Fortunately, the guy who gave me the K-Space tour also invited me to the Slack group, so I could still keep tabs on what was going on &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;. A half year went by, and I saw the following comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-year-2/year-2-image.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting. Pavel Kirienko? Sounds Russian/Ukrainian. I decided to Google his name and stumbled upon his GitHub. Then I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-year-2/year-2-image-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thought: alright, this guy is clearly one sick son-of-a-&lt;del&gt;bitch&lt;/del&gt; workaholic. He’s probably interesting. So, I sent him a PM asking if I could visit to see what he was working on. The rest, as they say, is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: for 8 more months, I would continue working at my consultancy job, growing gradually more frustrated. In the meantime, most of my free time was spent working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencyphal.org/&quot;&gt;OpenCyphal&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source project led by the previously mentioned Pavel. What happened at the end of those 8 months is actually a bit funny (and &lt;em&gt;classic&lt;/em&gt; me, if I may say so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many frustrating discussions with my Qualcomm colleagues where I was trying to expound on the benefits of writing tests (there were none; I had written something that could be used as such, but it was never going to get merged since it wasn’t something that was on their development roadmap), one fine morning at a standup with my colleagues, I announced that I would like to be transferred to a different project and that I wasn’t planning to work on anything Qualcomm-related going forward. My logic: “Worst case, they fire me, and that would be a blessing.” They fired me. Lucky for me, they gave me 3 months’ pay (if I remember correctly, it might have been 2). Get this: all this time, Pavel was telling me, “Don’t quit just yet; I can’t really hire you right now.” I texted him telling him what happened. The next day, I started to work at Zubax Robotics (for free). Fortunately, after a couple of months, Pavel managed to come through and pay me a salary. All’s well that ends well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember that once I was sitting on a bench in a park with my (then) girlfriend. She was applying for an Erasmus exchange program and had to write a cover letter explaining why she felt compelled to go study abroad. She asked me to read her letter to check her grammar and spelling and give some feedback. Her letter ended with a quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The mind, once stretched by a new idea, never returns to its original dimensions.” Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, being a sarcastic teenage boy, I made a bit of fun of this and said it was perhaps a bit too &lt;em&gt;Instagram-quotey&lt;/em&gt;. Ten years later, I’m ending this blog with the same quote.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2022</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/12/31/happy-new-year"/>
   <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/12/31/happy-new-year</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/kyiv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kyiv&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year has been unlike any other, it feels fitting to draw some conclusions and express some hopes for the future. As someone who grew up in a Russian family, it has been challenging to witness the events of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I have come to appreciate the benefits of being fluent in two very different cultures: Western and Eastern European. However, it has not always been easy to navigate these dual identities. I can easily pass as either Belgian or Russian, but often feel like I don’t fully belong to either. I imagine this is a common experience for children of immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, a revolution in Ukraine resulted in the overthrow of their Russian-backed president. I was a university student at the time and I recall watching the news in awe while sitting in the Arenberg library (I should have been studying). I believe that this was the first time I developed an interest in Ukraine as a country and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating from university, one of my best friends embarked on a round-the-world trip. The final leg of this trip involved taking the Trans-Siberian Express from Mongolia to Moscow. When he arrived, I called him up and suggested we meet up in Kyiv. I was interested in visiting the city and this was a good opportunity as any. As some of my friends can attest, I fell completely in love with Kyiv after this trip and even considered moving there for a while. I think the reason for this sudden infatuation was that I finally felt a sense of belonging: Ukraine is both free and culturally a hybrid of East and West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say this war has been a small personal tragedy for me. I already had little hope for Russia to develop in the direction that I wish it would. But now they were invading and bombing the only place that I could still feel home. Nevertheless, one positive aspect of this year that I would like to highlight is the inspiring bravery of the Ukrainian people and the way that the forces of good can come together to oppose evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as this year draws to a close: I would like to wish for a successful conclusion to the Ukrainian struggle for freedom. I’m sad it will have to come at such a cost, but will continue to do everything that is in my capabilities to help them, and hope you will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.help99.co/&quot;&gt;too&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>light.terminal</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/09/01/light-terminal"/>
   <updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/09/01/light-terminal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-terminal/light-terminal-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;images/light-terminal/light-terminal-header.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A payment terminal for light.pay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously we have introduced the idea for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maksimdrachov.github.io/2022/08/31/light-wallet&quot;&gt;light.wallet&lt;/a&gt;, a hardware wallet that uses a light-based protocol for transmitting information back-and-forth (called &lt;strong&gt;light.pay&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using the wallet in combination with a phone, each transaction takes somewhere between 1 to 3 minutes. As the primary use case of the wallet is to store value, it is safe to assume such withdrawals won’t need to be made very often. Indeed it might even be seen as a benefit: it introduces some friction whenever you want to withdraw, thereby encouraging you to hodl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as the adoption and usage of Bitcoin grows, increasingly it’ll be used as a regular currency as well (paying for groceries, taxi, coffee,…). To make these kind of daily transactions as quick and easy as possible, we want to introduce a new project: &lt;strong&gt;light.terminal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by taking a look at how a transaction is signed using the light.wallet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-terminal/lightpay-steps-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;lightpay-steps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps 1 and 3 use light.pay to transmit information back-and-forth. Assuming we use the phone’s camera (30 Hz) and screen (60 Hz); a transaction takes roughly 3 minutes. To optimize the user experience for daily transactions, we need a way to increase the speed of transmitting information between the wallet and the phone by multiple orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-terminal/light-terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;light-terminal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the light.terminal comes into play, it’s a square-shaped box that connects to the merchant’s phone. It integrates a light-sensor and LED (same setup as the light.wallet) and 2 magnets that allow for easy allignment between the sensors/leds of the terminal and the customer’s wallet. This circumvents the bottleneck in transmission speed, reducing the time it takes to make a payment down to a fraction of a second. This is done without requiring any special hardware (nfc, bluetooth, batteries) and works even with the most basic feature phone (which are popular in developing countries where we could envision this being used by cab drivers, street merchants,…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give credit where credit is due: we were (heavily) inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://squareup.com/us/en/hardware/reader&quot;&gt;Square card reader&lt;/a&gt;, which uses the same concept but applied to credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-terminal/square-card-reader.png&quot; alt=&quot;square-card-reader&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light.terminal allows for anyone to quickly setup a payment terminal that is as easy to use as the credit card, without needing to go through a centralized authority such as a bank or cryptocurrency exchange. This further decreases the barrier for anyone to start earning and doing business in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>light.wallet</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/08/31/light-wallet"/>
   <updated>2022-08-31T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/08/31/light-wallet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-wallet/light-wallet.png&quot; alt=&quot;light-wallet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A hardware wallet for the next billion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of a hardware wallet is nothing new. There are already lots of companies operating in this domain, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot;&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://trezor.io/&quot;&gt;Trezor&lt;/a&gt; being the most well-known. However, if one takes a closer look at the products currently on the market it becomes clear that there isn’t really anything that could scale to the next billion of users. This comes down to the following three factors: expensive, not user-friendly and not durable. The light.wallet offers a solution to all three problems, enabling the entrance of the next billion into safely storing and using Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-billion&quot;&gt;Next billion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis: Bitcoin will become the preferred currency of choice in developing countries &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the developed ones. Why? Our argument is that this mainly comes down to 2 factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High inflation: many developing countries suffer from high rates of inflation, investing in Bitcoin can be a hedge against this kind of instability and a reliable way to build wealth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.7 billion unbanked (&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalfindex.worldbank.org/sites/globalfindex/files/chapters/2017%20Findex%20full%20report_chapter2.pdf&quot;&gt;worldbank.org&lt;/a&gt;): “Globally, about 1.7 billion adults remain unbanked-without an account at a financial institution or through a mobile money provider.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest data seems to support this hypothesis. For example, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.chainalysis.com/rs/503-FAP-074/images/Geography-of-Cryptocurrency-2021.pdf&quot;&gt;2021 Geography of Cryptocurrency Report&lt;/a&gt; shows that the countries with the highest amount of P2P exchange volume (adjusted for PPP per capita) are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kenya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Togo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vietnam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tanzania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cameroon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-problem&quot;&gt;What’s the problem?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most users of crypto in the developing world use their (smart)phone as a wallet. However this has some significant downsides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loss/theft: given the fact that a phone is something carried daily, it is at a significant risk of being lost or stolen. Especially when this becomes your de-facto savings account this becomes an extremely high risk, an unfortunate accident/situation could mean losing all your funds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battery life: as smartphones are often prone to running out of battery, this means that you’re always dependent on having a charge whenever you want to make a transaction. This can be incredibly inconvenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to use a hardware wallet. However, if we take a look at the currently available models, we’ll see that they all carry significant downsides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ledger Nano S&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Requires a computer/usb-cable connection to use
- Not very durable/waterproof
- Making a transaction is cumbersome
- Expensive (€60)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trezor T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Requires a computer/usb-cable connection to use
- Not very durable/waterproof
- Making a transaction is cumbersome
- Expensive (€65)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ledger Nano X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+ Wireless (Bluetooth)
- Not very durable/waterproof
- (Prohibitively) expensive (€120)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coldcard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+ Does not require a computer (air-gap)
- Not very durable/waterproof
- (Prohibitively) expensive ($130)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-solution&quot;&gt;What’s the solution?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to this problem needs to check the following criteria/constraints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure: a secure wallet means that your funds can be stored safely, even if someone steals your wallet, they should not be able to access your funds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Durable: if it is to be adopted by a large number of people, living in a wide range of climates, it is clear that durability is an important feature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affordable: makes it accessible to the widest range of people, regardless of their financial situation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy-to-use: should not require any special knowledge/skills to use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KaiOS/Android: assume that the only internet-connected device available is a very basic phone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KaiOS&quot;&gt;KaiOS&lt;/a&gt; is a popular OS for (cheap) feature phones that nevertheless offer internet connectivity (and a small app store).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the light.wallet will look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-wallet/wallet-front-back.png&quot; alt=&quot;wallet-front-back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s go through the criteria one-by-one again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;secure&quot;&gt;Secure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security is based on a minimal attack surface principle. A common type of hack is called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Side-channel_attack&quot;&gt;side-channel attack&lt;/a&gt;” and is based on extracting information from the device through analysing power usage or detecting EM waves. By not providing any access to the battery (which can be charged by the solar cell), we can already effectively eliminate the possibility to analyse the power usage. By adding a metallic foil on the inside of the casing of the wallet, we also eliminate the possibility of extracting (or affecting) the data of the device through the use of EM waves. Finally, the device should be constructed in such a way that it can’t be disassembled without destroying the circuitry containing the private keys. All this should contribute to a wallet, which while simple in its approach, still offers plenty of security. As there is no need for any special secure electronic components, this approach also offers a high degree of security at the lowest price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;durable&quot;&gt;Durable&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no ports on the device, the keyboard is integrated in the casing as well, much in the same way as done on the 2FA-authentication device shown below. Waterproofing such a device should not be a great challenge and can be done quite cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-wallet/2fa-device.png&quot; alt=&quot;2fa-device&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;affordable&quot;&gt;Affordable&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our estimate is that a large part of the cost of other wallets comes from using special, expensive components such as secure elements or bluetooth chips. As our approach to security does not require any secure elements and the communication is mainly done through the keyboard and led/light-sensor, it should come at a significantly lower price-point that the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;easy-to-use&quot;&gt;Easy-to-use&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard offers an easy and universally understood interface (something which can’t be said for some other wallets). When transmission of data is required, this is done through VLC (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visible_light_communication&quot;&gt;Visible Light Communication&lt;/a&gt;) using the LED, giving a visual confirmation of the transaction to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;kaiosandroid&quot;&gt;KaiOS/Android&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming the most basic of phones with an internet connection, this wallet can still be used. The only requirement for making a transaction is a flash-light and a camera-module, which can be found on even the cheapest models (some of which don’t have Bluetooth).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already mentioned VLC, but what do we mean exactly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For making a transaction, a signing has to occur on the wallet and that signature (data) needs to be transmitted to the internet. Currently available wallets do this in one of 2 ways: USB or Bluetooth. Both have some significant downsides. USB requires an additional cable and a port which can be a liability when it comes to durability. Bluetooth is more expensive and uses additional power, leading to a reduced battery life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our solution is to integrate a LED and light-sensor on the back of the wallet, which can be used to communicate (in both directions) with the phone (which is in turn connected to the internet). A ‘basic’ bitcoin transaction requires ~250 bytes of data (2000 bits). Assuming that the phone camera has a refresh rate of 15 Hz, this means a transaction can be transmitted in ~2 minutes. Given the rate of improvement of smartphone cameras and the subsequent drop in cost, it is safe to assume that even the most basic phones will soon have 60 Hz cameras, which would result in a transmission time of ~35 seconds. As phone usage has wide penetration, even in the most remote parts of the world, this could mean a true revolution in terms of making payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-wallet/vlc-communication.png&quot; alt=&quot;vlc-communication&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;battery-life&quot;&gt;Battery life&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, let’s talk about battery life. Since there is no external way to charge the device, integration of a solar cell solves this by allowing it to easily be recharged by sunlight. Solar cells are, much in the same way as smartphone cameras, continually improving and getting cheaper and therefore should not cause a great increase in the final unit cost. On the power consumption side, we can also mention that by using VLC it should be possible to greatly reduce the required power in comparison to other wireless solutions such as Bluetooth. In the end, the product life of this wallet will be measured in years (or even decades).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light.wallet offers a completely new approach to hardware wallets, with the potential to play a crucial role in the further adoption of Bitcoin around the world. Our hope is that it can become the Nokia 3310 of hardware wallets and just as ubiquitous. We believe that by empowering everyone to become their own bank, the world will become more prosperous and fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maksimdrachov.github.io/2022/09/01/light-terminal&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>estonia: month 1</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/03/05/estonia-month-1"/>
   <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/03/05/estonia-month-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been roughly a month since I moved to Estonia and &lt;em&gt;boy&lt;/em&gt; what a rollercoaster of a month it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-people&quot;&gt;meeting people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my main reason for moving here was to get closer to a “real” startup scene, this month has been all about going to meetups, talking to people and visiting spaces (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lift99.co/&quot;&gt;Lift99&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k-space.ee/&quot;&gt;K-space&lt;/a&gt;). Let’s go over some of the interesting people I’ve met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Miao (CTO @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superfluid.finance/home&quot;&gt;Superfluid&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miao was one of the first people I got to know (during a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Tallinn-Libertarian-Meetup/&quot;&gt;Libertarian meetup&lt;/a&gt;). He works on Superfluid, which is a blockchain-based protocol that allows you to &lt;em&gt;stream&lt;/em&gt; money. What does this mean? Well, basically: in the future you won’t get paid x amount every &lt;em&gt;month&lt;/em&gt;, but x amount every &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of how this could work: imagine you’re a highly-skilled programmer, you don’t have an employer but merely ‘rent’ out your time to anyone willing to pay your rate. You could be working for a couple of hours in the morning on one project for one company, and a couple of hours in the afternoon on another project for another company. Your compensation is on a second-by-second basis: at the end of the day you’ll see that your wallet has been topped up by the exact amount you’ve earned that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the spending side, this also increases flexibility. Let’s say you’re not really interested in a monthly Netflix subscription, however sometimes Netflix does release something &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/ee/title/81426972&quot;&gt;worth&lt;/a&gt; watching. Using Superfluid it would be possible to pay Netflix on a per-second basis, which would allow me to finally stop leaching on my sisters account (sorry). For more examples, check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superfluid.finance/home&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first visit to Lift99 I got lucky: it was the evening before Independence day, which meant there was a party. Miao was also there and after a couple of shots of Estonian vodka, he was kind enough to give me a small demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-month-1/superfluid.png&quot; alt=&quot;images/estonia-month-1/superfluid.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superfluid in action&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short setup procedure he was streaming me $10/month (which resulted in me receiving 0.0725$ at the time when the screenshot was taken). Cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rasmus (Senior Technical Advisor @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pawapay.co.uk/&quot;&gt;pawaPay&lt;/a&gt;, CTO @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.betpawa.cm/&quot;&gt;betPawa&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally from Denmark, Rasmus is a co-founder of betPawa, an online sport betting platform that is mainly active in Africa. After many years of (successfully) growing this company, he has decided to exit and dedicate more time to studying Bitcoin. Currently in the process of translating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Bitcoin-Standard-Decentralized-Alternative-Central/dp/1119473861&quot;&gt;“The Bitcoin Standard”&lt;/a&gt; into Danish, a book I can highly recommend to anyone (don’t worry it’s not technical, but focuses instead on the philosophical/cultural aspects of Bitcoin).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only met him once, so can’t tell much more, but I’m sure we’ll meet up again someday soon, eventually I want to discuss my own plans with him and hopefully get some valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marten (Co-founder @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinothers.com/&quot;&gt;Others&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My very first Estonian! Marten is one of the founders of Others, a company that sells an enviromentaly-friendly alternative to tooth paste. Seems like a cool dude, but I don’t remember as much, since by the time we spoke the vodka was finished (don’t worry there was still plenty of Estonian beer left) and so our conversation steered towards the metaphysical, but that would take us too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-month-1/others.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;images/estonia-month-1/others.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Packaging: on point&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, quite the international crowd (also have spoken with people from: Brazil, Sweden, France, Kazakhstan). For me this is the big &lt;em&gt;tell&lt;/em&gt; of any successful startup scene: it attracts talent globally.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>estonia: week 1</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/02/05/estonia-week-1"/>
   <updated>2022-02-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/02/05/estonia-week-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discussed in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;_posts/2021-12-24-moving-to-estonia.md&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; I have decided to move to Estonia. Now it has been roughly a week that I have found myself living in this new country and it feels like a good time to reflect on how this experience has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-move&quot;&gt;the move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unikie.com/en/&quot;&gt;Unikie&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago (remotely) from Belgium, however this was a temporary measure as I still needed to close the loop on some administrative tasks, such as terminating my lease for the appartment and packing up my stuff. I wanted to move as quickly as possible so the move was planned for the last weekend of January when I would pack everything into my car and drive from Belgium to Estonia. The move has been quite the adventure to say the least. The drive itself would be spread across 2 days; first from Brussels to Warsaw, and the second leg of the trip from Warsaw to Tallinn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/vw-polo-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;vw-polo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a relatively small car: a Volkswagen Polo. This meant that I would be packing only the essentials: clothing, a desk, a monitor; some books and some plants (those have already been with me from my university days so they have some sentimental value). The first day went reasonably well as the main part of the journey took place on the German Autobahn. I arrived in Warsaw somewhere around 11pm, slept in the cheapest hotel room I could find, woke up somewhere around 6am to continue the journey northwards to Tallinn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day proved to be a lot more challenging, at this point my ass had turned to stone from the lack of ergonomics of my car seat, which probably was never meant for such lengthy road trips anyway. Despite this, I had to persevere, I still had some 12 hours of driving ahead of me. As I was driving through the Baltics the conditions took a turn for the worse. You see I didn’t anticipate on arriving in Estonia during one hell of a snow blizzard. While tanking I received the following message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/screenshot-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shit&lt;/em&gt;. Well by that point I had already been driving through horrible weather for quite some already, and anyway I was &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; close to Tallinn so it didn’t really make sense to stop now. I think you can already feel where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/estonian-border.png&quot; alt=&quot;estonian-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crossing the Estonian border&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the weather conditions my estimated time of arrival kept being pushed forwards, as I had already realised that despite my winter tires my brakes weren’t worth much, I kept my speed limited to somewhere around 60 km/h: I would rather arrive late than not at all. Unfortunately some Estonian tractor-driver had other plans…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;30 km from Tallinn&lt;/em&gt;. I was driving down a slippery hill slope, on the side of the road a tractor was pushing snow. Ok, I thought: no problem. I can keep driving as he isn’t in my way. As I’m driving down the hill however the tractor-driver suddenly decides that it’s a good time to reverse back onto the road thereby blocking my way: he obviously didn’t look to see if anyone was coming his way. Despite my best effort there was no way I could stop in time, my attempt to dodge him was in vain as well. I first crashed with my right side into his rear, and then with my left into the guard rail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/crash-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;crash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck&lt;/em&gt;. I had crashed and was still in the middle of the road, as I realized this I quickly reversed and drove to the side of the road to clear the way so as to not cause a chain collision (this turned out to be a mistake as the police couldn’t come to judge the situation anymore). I jumped out to check the damage and realised: I’m not getting to Tallinn in this car anymore. A lot of discussion later the tractor driver left to continue his work, and I was stranded, waiting for the towing service to come pick me up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 1am I arrived to my hotel in Tallinn, I was tired and went to sleep, tomorrow would be my first day working at the office. Not a great start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-week&quot;&gt;the first week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately my first week seems to have gone by without any other serious accidents. I have gotten to know my colleagues, which is quite an international group: two Fins, one Russian, one Indian and one Estonian. Also I also managed to find an apartment that is super cosy and has a running track nearby (something I first discovered in Leuven and can’t do without since).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/app-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;app-view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cosy view from the appartment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some expectations of Estonia as a technologically advanced country, something which I already alluded to in the previous post and I haven’t been dissapointed. It’s the little things that it manifests itself in: the arangement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ulemistecity.ee/en/&quot;&gt;Ulemiste&lt;/a&gt; (area where I go to work) which has all the ammenities one could need for daily life right nearby: a tram station that makes going to work effortless (which is regular &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; free), a post box to get all your packages delivered, an international house for any questions you might have as an expat (and free language courses); there’s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://telliskivi.cc/en/&quot;&gt;Telliskivi&lt;/a&gt;: a supercool “hipster” area (my first reaction: this looks like Berlin, even though I’ve never been there). Something else which I’ve already been expecting but has been confirmed is the &lt;em&gt;forward lookingness&lt;/em&gt; of all the services. One good example is my bank account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lhv.ee/en&quot;&gt;LHV&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at their website, it reminds me a bit of Apple in how clean it looks and how clearly everything is organised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/lhv.png&quot; alt=&quot;lhv&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A small detail: you can invest in Bitcoin directly from you bank account&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, despite my somewhat chaotic arrival, I’m still very happy about taking the jump and am looking forward to all the new experiences this place has to offer. &lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>moving to estonia</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2021/12/24/moving-to-estonia"/>
   <updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2021/12/24/moving-to-estonia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made the decision to move to Estonia. In this post I’m going to chart out my reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some background: I’m 27 years old, studied Electrical Engineering at KU Leuven and am currently living in Belgium. Since finishing my studies I have worked at Nokia and then 2 different startups (as an early employee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will split up my argument in two parts: why I decided to leave Belgium and why I chose Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-im-leaving&quot;&gt;why I’m leaving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belgium is a well-developed country, so it might seem like a strange choice to leave. My reasons for leaving are probably not going to apply for most people, since they have mostly to do with my dream of becoming a startup founder. It is only when taking this into account, that it becomes clear why I felt staying was not the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;High tax burden&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the level of service offered by the Belgian government, I would argue the tax burden is quite high. For example, a couple of months ago I posted the following on my LinkedIn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/linkedin.png&quot; alt=&quot;linkedin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The link below gives a template for every kind of contract you could need as a start-up in Estonia. How come I can’t find something similar for Belgium?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tagged every one of our ministers (remember: 6 governments) that could have made a difference in solving this question. 1600 people saw the post, no one got back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem trivial, however to me this is part of a larger problem. The political class does not really care about improving the system as it is too busy with infighting. The Belgian state has become essentialy ossified in a political stalemate during the last decade or so, prohibiting any meaningful progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably in no small part due to the previous point, the Belgian startup ecosystem is quite underdeveloped. From my observation smart people do one of two things: work at large, established companies or move abroad. Belgium has 2 unicorns, the Netherlands has 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, there is one notable exception: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imec-int.com/en&quot;&gt;Imec&lt;/a&gt;, an R&amp;amp;D hub for nano- and digital technologies. This organization has succesfully spun-off multiple startups in its specialist field. However those are often based on specialization in a very narrow field of research. I’m more into the Silicon Valley-type of startups. (Sidenote: Imec was founded in 1984 when the Belgian state was still capable of undertaking such visionary projects.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Culture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally and this is more subjective point: there isn’t really much of a culture of entrepreneurship. Most young people don’t necessarily have the ambition to start something, and prefer to focus on having a steady, safe and predictable lifestyle. Nothing wrong with that. However it is a bit tiring for a person like me, as I often feel like the only one swimming against the current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-estonia&quot;&gt;why Estonia?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my interest in startups, I wanted to move someplace which would be more supportive of this. I started looking into all the most “popular” startup cities in Europe (didn’t want to move too far from home either). This essentially boils down to the usual suspects: London, Amsterdam, Stockholm, Paris and Berlin. Unfortunately most of them are prohibitively expensive, which would mean exchanging a high tax burden for a high cost of living, which wasn’t much of an improvement either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at this point Estonia was already on my radar (thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/balajis&quot;&gt;@balajis&lt;/a&gt;) as a country with some very foward-thinking policies when it came to digital governance. So I decided to take it into consideration as well. The more I looked into it, the more I became convinced it was the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember how Belgium had 2 unicorns? Estonia has 7. This becomes even more impressive when you consider the fact that Estonia has a population that’s roughly ten times smaller. This is no accident, a place that has the highest amount of unicorns per capita in Europe, obviously must be doing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; right. In my opinion 3 factors play into this success: favorable environment, network-effects, attraction of talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorable environment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was looking into Berlin as a candidate for my next move, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://peerrich.com/posts/how-i-would-start-my-next-startup-in-germany-without-a-gmbh&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article. It details the hoops that a German founder has to jump through in order to start a company. In short: it’s a very bureaucratic, kafka-esque experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia offers the exact opposite: it minimizes the administrative hurdle by allowing everything to be done online. Registering a company and paying taxes can all be done from your laptop. I have seen first-hand how bookkeeping can quickly become a one-man job in a Belgian startup, often one of the founders needs to take care of this. This means less time spent on what’s important: building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Network effects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a favorable environment, a startup culture can develop and as the amount of succesful startup grows, the collective experience of the ecosystem increases and the odds of success with it. For the past decade Silicon Valley has been the most obvious example of this. One of the most famous “networks” within Silicon Valley is the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PayPal_Mafia&quot;&gt;Paypal mafia&lt;/a&gt;”, which is a group of founders and employees affeliated with the early days of Paypal. These people gained valuable resources, knowledge and contacts from those early wins at Paypal and then leveraged this towards founding new startups: Tesla, Linkedin, Palantir, SpaceX, Youtube,…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something similar can be observed in Estonia: the term “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lift99.co/walloffame&quot;&gt;Estonian mafia&lt;/a&gt;” is already starting to gain some traction. Founders and early employees from companies like Skype, Bolt and Transferwise are going on to start new successful companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attraction of talent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least: attraction of talent. Silicon Valley couldn’t become what it is today if it didn’t attract the brighthest from across the globe. Here again, Estonia is helped by forward-thinking policies like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-resident.gov.ee/&quot;&gt;E-residency&lt;/a&gt; program and its historial ties with Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E-recidency allows anyone (even non-EU!) access to the Estonian government services such as company formation, banking, payment processing and taxation. This makes attracting talent from across the globe considerably easier, especially as we move more and more towards a remote-first world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that second point: lots of talented programmers and engineers from Ukraine, Belarus and Russia have moved to Estonia to escape the unstable political/economical climate in their respective countries. This is a massive talent pool to draw from. As Estonia has a long history with Eastern Europe, it allows them to more easily incorporate people from this cultural background into their fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that by moving to Tallinn I will be able to develop the skills to become a founder more quickly and increase the odds of my startup being successful. If you live in Tallinn and share my interest in startups: would love to have a beer! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found this interesting and want to find out more about Estonia, I can recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startupestonia.ee/&quot;&gt;startupestonia.ee&lt;/a&gt;: gives a very clear overview of the Estonian startup ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZqVkdpDBrkCJVqL-s-aiPA&quot;&gt;Startup in Estonia&lt;/a&gt;: interviews with Estonian founders. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-matT605ss&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; episode I found the most inspiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
