<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>dra4ov</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/"/>
 <updated>2022-05-22T14:14:51+03:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>revolutions</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/05/21/revolutions"/>
   <updated>2022-05-21T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/05/21/revolutions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/revolutions/apple-mac.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;apple-mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internet&quot;&gt;internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, civilization is radically transformed through technological revolutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food production (Agricultural Revolution, ~8000 BC)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Industry (Industrial Revolution, ~1760)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electrical power (Second Industrial Revolution, ~1880)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet (Information Revolution, ~1990)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Information Revolution is the latest addition to this list and therefore the one whose full impact still remains to be felt. The internet allows for two (seemingly) contradictory trends to occur simultanously: increasing equality and increasing inequality. How can this be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing &lt;em&gt;equality&lt;/em&gt;: An internet connection is the great equalizer when it comes to leveling the playing field in terms of access to information. This gives everyone the opportunity to educate themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing &lt;em&gt;inequality&lt;/em&gt;: Equality of opportunity does not result in equality of outcome. Even though everyone has the same opportunity; the internet offers many rabit holes: some are more useful than others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of the internet has occured in &lt;em&gt;waves&lt;/em&gt;, some notable ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;web 1.0 (Amazon, Google, Paypal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;web 2.0
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;social media (Facebook, Youtube, Instagram)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;apps (Uber, Deliveroo, Tinder)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web 1.0 was the first wave of (centralized) internet services such as Amazon, Google and Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web 2.0 was the first step towards a more peer-to-peer based form of human interconnection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies, such as Facebook, Youtube and Twitter, gave everyone a platform to express themselves, and replaced previous, centrally-controlled, information sources such as TV networks and newspapers. Arguably some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Revolution&quot;&gt;revolutions&lt;/a&gt; wouldn’t have occured, were it not for this latest addition to humanity’s toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphones have further increased the scope of possible applications: press a button, a cab arrives; press a button, dinner; press a button, a date. (No guarantees on that last one though!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently we find ourselves in the early stages of the third wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/revolutions/steve-iphone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;steve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitcoin&quot;&gt;bitcoin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a fundamental upgrade to the Internet Protocol: initially we got e-mail, now we have e-money. Going back to our previous discussion about the internet being a great equalizer in terms of access to information; one problem that still didn’t solve: lack of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine a child in the Amazon learns to program from Youtube videos. How would he monetize his skills? His village might not require many software engineers; paying him from across the internet in his local currency would also be pretty difficult. Now however, using Bitcoin, making a payment can be as easy as sending an e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The further &lt;em&gt;bitcoinization&lt;/em&gt; of the world will occur slowly and then suddenly. It might seem like a small thing being able to send money, however in hindsight: e-mail was merely a prelude for what was to come. The consequences will be massive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin allows for the rise of completely new kinds of decentralized organizations. The first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.comparably.com/news/20-companies-that-are-now-remote-first-or-fully-remote/&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of remote-first companies have already started to show up (with some help from China). Bitcoin will only further accelerate this trend, erasing the arbitrary economic borders imposed by the hegemony of national currencies. First, the internet provided everyone access to information; soon it will provide everyone access to opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/revolutions/satoshi.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;satoshi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;The creator of Bitcoin remains anonymous to this day.&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>estonia: month 1</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/03/05/estonia-month-1"/>
   <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/03/05/estonia-month-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been roughly a month since I moved to Estonia and &lt;em&gt;boy&lt;/em&gt; what a rollercoaster of a month it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-people&quot;&gt;meeting people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my main reason for moving here was to get closer to a “real” startup scene, this month has been all about going to meetups, talking to people and visiting spaces (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lift99.co/&quot;&gt;Lift99&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k-space.ee/&quot;&gt;K-space&lt;/a&gt;). Let’s go over some of the interesting people I’ve met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Miao (CTO @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superfluid.finance/home&quot;&gt;Superfluid&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miao was one of the first people I got to know (during a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Tallinn-Libertarian-Meetup/&quot;&gt;Libertarian meetup&lt;/a&gt;). He works on Superfluid, which is a blockchain-based protocol that allows you to &lt;em&gt;stream&lt;/em&gt; money. What does this mean? Well, basically: in the future you won’t get paid x amount every &lt;em&gt;month&lt;/em&gt;, but x amount every &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of how this could work: imagine you’re a highly-skilled programmer, you don’t have an employer but merely ‘rent’ out your time to anyone willing to pay your rate. You could be working for a couple of hours in the morning on one project for one company, and a couple of hours in the afternoon on another project for another company. Your compensation is on a second-by-second basis: at the end of the day you’ll see that your wallet has been topped up by the exact amount you’ve earned that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the spending side, this also increases flexibility. Let’s say you’re not really interested in a monthly Netflix subscription, however sometimes Netflix does release something &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/ee/title/81426972&quot;&gt;worth&lt;/a&gt; watching. Using Superfluid it would be possible to pay Netflix on a per-second basis, which would allow me to finally stop leaching on my sisters account (sorry). For more examples, check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superfluid.finance/home&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first visit to Lift99 I got lucky: it was the evening before Independence day, which meant there was a party. Miao was also there and after a couple of shots of Estonian vodka, he was kind enough to give me a small demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-month-1/superfluid.png&quot; alt=&quot;images/estonia-month-1/superfluid.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superfluid in action&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short setup procedure he was streaming me $10/month (which resulted in me receiving 0.0725$ at the time when the screenshot was taken). Cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rasmus (Senior Technical Advisor @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pawapay.co.uk/&quot;&gt;pawaPay&lt;/a&gt;, CTO @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.betpawa.cm/&quot;&gt;betPawa&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally from Denmark, Rasmus is a co-founder of betPawa, an online sport betting platform that is mainly active in Africa. After many years of (successfully) growing this company, he has decided to exit and dedicate more time to studying Bitcoin. Currently in the process of translating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Bitcoin-Standard-Decentralized-Alternative-Central/dp/1119473861&quot;&gt;“The Bitcoin Standard”&lt;/a&gt; into Danish, a book I can highly recommend to anyone (don’t worry it’s not technical, but focuses instead on the philosophical/cultural aspects of Bitcoin).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only met him once, so can’t tell much more, but I’m sure we’ll meet up again someday soon, eventually I want to discuss my own plans with him and hopefully get some valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marten (Co-founder @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinothers.com/&quot;&gt;Others&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My very first Estonian! Marten is one of the founders of Others, a company that sells an enviromentaly-friendly alternative to tooth paste. Seems like a cool dude, but I don’t remember as much, since by the time we spoke the vodka was finished (don’t worry there was still plenty of Estonian beer left) and so our conversation steered towards the metaphysical, but that would take us too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-month-1/others.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;images/estonia-month-1/others.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Packaging: on point&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, quite the international crowd (also have spoken with people from: Brazil, Sweden, France, Kazakhstan). For me this is the big &lt;em&gt;tell&lt;/em&gt; of any successful startup scene: it attracts talent globally.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>estonia: week 1</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2022/02/05/estonia-week-1"/>
   <updated>2022-02-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2022/02/05/estonia-week-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discussed in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;_posts/2021-12-24-moving-to-estonia.md&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; I have decided to move to Estonia. Now it has been roughly a week that I have found myself living in this new country and it feels like a good time to reflect on how this experience has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-move&quot;&gt;the move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unikie.com/en/&quot;&gt;Unikie&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago (remotely) from Belgium, however this was a temporary measure as I still needed to close the loop on some administrative tasks, such as terminating my lease for the appartment and packing up my stuff. I wanted to move as quickly as possible so the move was planned for the last weekend of January when I would pack everything into my car and drive from Belgium to Estonia. The move has been quite the adventure to say the least. The drive itself would be spread across 2 days; first from Brussels to Warsaw, and the second leg of the trip from Warsaw to Tallinn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/vw-polo-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;vw-polo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a relatively small car: a Volkswagen Polo. This meant that I would be packing only the essentials: clothing, a desk, a monitor; some books and some plants (those have already been with me from my university days so they have some sentimental value). The first day went reasonably well as the main part of the journey took place on the German Autobahn. I arrived in Warsaw somewhere around 11pm, slept in the cheapest hotel room I could find, woke up somewhere around 6am to continue the journey northwards to Tallinn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day proved to be a lot more challenging, at this point my ass had turned to stone from the lack of ergonomics of my car seat, which probably was never meant for such lengthy road trips anyway. Despite this, I had to persevere, I still had some 12 hours of driving ahead of me. As I was driving through the Baltics the conditions took a turn for the worse. You see I didn’t anticipate on arriving in Estonia during one hell of a snow blizzard. While tanking I received the following message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/screenshot-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shit&lt;/em&gt;. Well by that point I had already been driving through horrible weather for quite some already, and anyway I was &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; close to Tallinn so it didn’t really make sense to stop now. I think you can already feel where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/estonian-border.png&quot; alt=&quot;estonian-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crossing the Estonian border&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the weather conditions my estimated time of arrival kept being pushed forwards, as I had already realised that despite my winter tires my brakes weren’t worth much, I kept my speed limited to somewhere around 60 km/h: I would rather arrive late than not at all. Unfortunately some Estonian tractor-driver had other plans…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;30 km from Tallinn&lt;/em&gt;. I was driving down a slippery hill slope, on the side of the road a tractor was pushing snow. Ok, I thought: no problem. I can keep driving as he isn’t in my way. As I’m driving down the hill however the tractor-driver suddenly decides that it’s a good time to reverse back onto the road thereby blocking my way: he obviously didn’t look to see if anyone was coming his way. Despite my best effort there was no way I could stop in time, my attempt to dodge him was in vain as well. I first crashed with my right side into his rear, and then with my left into the guard rail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/crash-resized.png&quot; alt=&quot;crash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck&lt;/em&gt;. I had crashed and was still in the middle of the road, as I realized this I quickly reversed and drove to the side of the road to clear the way so as to not cause a chain collision (this turned out to be a mistake as the police couldn’t come to judge the situation anymore). I jumped out to check the damage and realised: I’m not getting to Tallinn in this car anymore. A lot of discussion later the tractor driver left to continue his work, and I was stranded, waiting for the towing service to come pick me up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 1am I arrived to my hotel in Tallinn, I was tired and went to sleep, tomorrow would be my first day working at the office. Not a great start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-week&quot;&gt;the first week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately my first week seems to have gone by without any other serious accidents. I have gotten to know my colleagues, which is quite an international group: two Fins, one Russian, one Indian and one Estonian. Also I also managed to find an apartment that is super cosy and has a running track nearby (something I first discovered in Leuven and can’t do without since).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/app-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;app-view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cosy view from the appartment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some expectations of Estonia as a technologically advanced country, something which I already alluded to in the previous post and I haven’t been dissapointed. It’s the little things that it manifests itself in: the arangement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ulemistecity.ee/en/&quot;&gt;Ulemiste&lt;/a&gt; (area where I go to work) which has all the ammenities one could need for daily life right nearby: a tram station that makes going to work effortless (which is regular &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; free), a post box to get all your packages delivered, an international house for any questions you might have as an expat (and free language courses); there’s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://telliskivi.cc/en/&quot;&gt;Telliskivi&lt;/a&gt;: a supercool “hipster” area (my first reaction: this looks like Berlin, even though I’ve never been there). Something else which I’ve already been expecting but has been confirmed is the &lt;em&gt;forward lookingness&lt;/em&gt; of all the services. One good example is my bank account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lhv.ee/en&quot;&gt;LHV&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at their website, it reminds me a bit of Apple in how clean it looks and how clearly everything is organised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/estonia-week-1/lhv.png&quot; alt=&quot;lhv&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A small detail: you can invest in Bitcoin directly from you bank account&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, despite my somewhat chaotic arrival, I’m still very happy about taking the jump and am looking forward to all the new experiences this place has to offer. &lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>moving to estonia</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2021/12/24/moving-to-estonia"/>
   <updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2021/12/24/moving-to-estonia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/e-estonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;estonia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made the decision to move to Estonia. In this post I’m going to chart out my reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some background: I’m 27 years old, studied Electrical Engineering at KU Leuven and am currently living in Belgium. Since finishing my studies I have worked at Nokia and then 2 different startups (as an early employee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will split up my argument in two parts: why I decided to leave Belgium and why I chose Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-im-leaving&quot;&gt;why I’m leaving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belgium is a well-developed country, so it might seem like a strange choice to leave. My reasons for leaving are probably not going to apply for most people, since they have mostly to do with my dream of becoming a startup founder. It is only when taking this into account, that it becomes clear why I felt staying was not the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;High tax burden&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the level of service offered by the Belgian government, I would argue the tax burden is quite high. For example, a couple of months ago I posted the following on my LinkedIn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moving-to-estonia/linkedin.png&quot; alt=&quot;linkedin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The link below gives a template for every kind of contract you could need as a start-up in Estonia. How come I can’t find something similar for Belgium?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tagged every one of our ministers (remember: 6 governments) that could have made a difference in solving this question. 1600 people saw the post, no one got back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem trivial, however to me this is part of a larger problem. The political class does not really care about improving the system as it is too busy with infighting. The Belgian state has become essentialy ossified in a political stalemate during the last decade or so, prohibiting any meaningful progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably in no small part due to the previous point, the Belgian startup ecosystem is quite underdeveloped. From my observation smart people do one of two things: work at large, established companies or move abroad. Belgium has 2 unicorns, the Netherlands has 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, there is one notable exception: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imec-int.com/en&quot;&gt;Imec&lt;/a&gt;, an R&amp;amp;D hub for nano- and digital technologies. This organization has succesfully spun-off multiple startups in its specialist field. However those are often based on specialization in a very narrow field of research. I’m more into the Silicon Valley-type of startups. (Sidenote: Imec was founded in 1984 when the Belgian state was still capable of undertaking such visionary projects.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Culture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally and this is more subjective point: there isn’t really much of a culture of entrepreneurship. Most young people don’t necessarily have the ambition to start something, and prefer to focus on having a steady, safe and predictable lifestyle. Nothing wrong with that. However it is a bit tiring for a person like me, as I often feel like the only one swimming against the current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-estonia&quot;&gt;why Estonia?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my interest in startups, I wanted to move someplace which would be more supportive of this. I started looking into all the most “popular” startup cities in Europe (didn’t want to move too far from home either). This essentially boils down to the usual suspects: London, Amsterdam, Stockholm, Paris and Berlin. Unfortunately most of them are prohibitively expensive, which would mean exchanging a high tax burden for a high cost of living, which wasn’t much of an improvement either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at this point Estonia was already on my radar (thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/balajis&quot;&gt;@balajis&lt;/a&gt;) as a country with some very foward-thinking policies when it came to digital governance. So I decided to take it into consideration as well. The more I looked into it, the more I became convinced it was the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember how Belgium had 2 unicorns? Estonia has 7. This becomes even more impressive when you consider the fact that Estonia has a population that’s roughly ten times smaller. This is no accident, a place that has the highest amount of unicorns per capita in Europe, obviously must be doing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; right. In my opinion 3 factors play into this success: favorable environment, network-effects, attraction of talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorable environment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was looking into Berlin as a candidate for my next move, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://peerrich.com/posts/how-i-would-start-my-next-startup-in-germany-without-a-gmbh&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article. It details the hoops that a German founder has to jump through in order to start a company. In short: it’s a very bureaucratic, kafka-esque experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia offers the exact opposite: it minimizes the administrative hurdle by allowing everything to be done online. Registering a company and paying taxes can all be done from your laptop. I have seen first-hand how bookkeeping can quickly become a one-man job in a Belgian startup, often one of the founders needs to take care of this. This means less time spent on what’s important: building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Network effects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a favorable environment, a startup culture can develop and as the amount of succesful startup grows, the collective experience of the ecosystem increases and the odds of success with it. For the past decade Silicon Valley has been the most obvious example of this. One of the most famous “networks” within Silicon Valley is the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PayPal_Mafia&quot;&gt;Paypal mafia&lt;/a&gt;”, which is a group of founders and employees affeliated with the early days of Paypal. These people gained valuable resources, knowledge and contacts from those early wins at Paypal and then leveraged this towards founding new startups: Tesla, Linkedin, Palantir, SpaceX, Youtube,…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something similar can be observed in Estonia: the term “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lift99.co/walloffame&quot;&gt;Estonian mafia&lt;/a&gt;” is already starting to gain some traction. Founders and early employees from companies like Skype, Bolt and Transferwise are going on to start new successful companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attraction of talent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least: attraction of talent. Silicon Valley couldn’t become what it is today if it didn’t attract the brighthest from across the globe. Here again, Estonia is helped by forward-thinking policies like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-resident.gov.ee/&quot;&gt;E-residency&lt;/a&gt; program and its historial ties with Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E-recidency allows anyone (even non-EU!) access to the Estonian government services such as company formation, banking, payment processing and taxation. This makes attracting talent from across the globe considerably easier, especially as we move more and more towards a remote-first world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that second point: lots of talented programmers and engineers from Ukraine, Belarus and Russia have moved to Estonia to escape the unstable political/economical climate in their respective countries. This is a massive talent pool to draw from. As Estonia has a long history with Eastern Europe, it allows them to more easily incorporate people from this cultural background into their fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that by moving to Tallinn I will be able to develop the skills to become a founder more quickly and increase the odds of my startup being successful. If you live in Tallinn and share my interest in startups: would love to have a beer! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found this interesting and want to find out more about Estonia, I can recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startupestonia.ee/&quot;&gt;startupestonia.ee&lt;/a&gt;: gives a very clear overview of the Estonian startup ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZqVkdpDBrkCJVqL-s-aiPA&quot;&gt;Startup in Estonia&lt;/a&gt;: interviews with Estonian founders. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-matT605ss&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; episode I found the most inspiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
