<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>dra4ov</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/"/>
 <updated>2021-08-14T10:57:25+02:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Tutorials</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/2021/08/12/tutorials"/>
   <updated>2021-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/2021/08/12/tutorials</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently I’m writing a tutorial on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/maksimdrachov/zephyr-rtos-tutorial&quot;&gt;Zephyr RTOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of topics under consideration for future tutorials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zephyr Tutorial for Advanced Topics&lt;/em&gt;: A tutorial that picks up the thread where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/maksimdrachov/zephyr-rtos-tutorial&quot;&gt;beginners tutorial&lt;/a&gt; leaves off. Some of the topics that I’d like to cover are: bluetooth, bootloader, security (trusted firmware), cryptography (how it applies to blockchain),…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blockchain for Embedded Developers&lt;/em&gt;: A tutorial series on how to work with blockchain on embedded devices. I’ve already started to compile a bunch of interesting resources &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/maksimdrachov/awesome-embedded-blockchain&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Renode&lt;/em&gt;: Renode is an open source software development framework with commercial support from Antmicro that lets you develop, debug and test multi-node device systems reliably, scalably and effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Linux Kernel&lt;/em&gt;: The Linux kernel is a free and open-source, monolithic, modular, multitasking, Unix-like operating system kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/em&gt;: The Internet protocol suite, commonly known as TCP/IP, is the set of communications protocols used in the Internet and similar computer networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
