<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-03T16:27:02+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">drachov</title><subtitle>to serve and inspire
</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;maksim.drachov@outlook.com&quot;}</name><email>maksim.drachov@outlook.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Manifesto</title><link href="/2018/01/01/manifesto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manifesto" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/01/01/manifesto</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/01/01/manifesto.html">&lt;p&gt;A vision. Of a place where people can come together and have meaningful conversations about the future, which is given shape by young people doing the out of ordinary, not giving in to the societal pressures of their particular time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driven by the desire to do things for the greater good, not the bigger profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To not make an excessive amount of noise about “values”, the actions should speak for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence that a better world is possible and necessary. Knowledge that it is up to each individual to contribute to that better world. By working, not talking, by creating the new, reinventing the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rising beyond our collective past, to not let old history or ideas rule our current time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Courageous enough to speak the truth, no matter the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give Europe, which has become ideologically bankrupt, a new direction for the 21st century. A transfusion of fresh blood, of new ideas. To make history once again. Rekindle the flame of an exploratory spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encourage young people to pursue a meaningful life. Encourage excellence and perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not rail against corporations, governments,… as long as they are not in our way of achieving our goals. Instead we continue to work alongside and if necessary within these old concepts to bring about the changes we desire to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good life is not the absence of suffering, but the presence of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/photos/kiev.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kiev_photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Maksim Drachov&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">A vision. Of a place where people can come together and have meaningful conversations about the future, which is given shape by young people doing the out of ordinary, not giving in to the societal pressures of their particular time.</summary></entry></feed>